Correctional Association of New York; Records apap014
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Annual Reports, 1844-1979; 2; 11 reels of 35 mm microfilm and bound copies
  - 100th Annual Report 3 unnumbered plates., 1944 (Reel 10, Page 1-126)
  - 101st Annual Report 4 unnumbered plates., 1945 (Reel 10, Page 1-125)
  - 102nd Annual Report 6 unnumbered plates., 1946 (Reel 10, Page 1-134)
  - 103rd Annual Report 3 unnumbered plates., 1947 (Reel 10, Page 1-114)
  - 104th Annual Report 8 unnumbered plates., 1948 (Reel 10, Page 1-102)
  - 105th Annual Report, 1949 (Reel 10, Page 1-98)
  - 106th Annual Report, 1950 (Reel 10, Page 1-93)
  - 107th Annual Report, 1951 (Reel 10, Page 1-105)
  - 108th Annual Report, 1952 (Reel 10, Page 1-89)
  - 109th Annual Report, 1953 (Reel 10, Page 1-97)
  - 110th Annual Report, 1954 (Reel 10, Page 1-94)
  - 111th Annual Report, 1955 (Reel 10, Page 1-96)
  - 112th Annual Report, 1956 (Reel 10, Page 1-106)
  - 113th Annual Report, 1957 (Reel 10, Page 1-118)
  - 114th Annual Report, 1958 (Reel 10, Page 1-95)
  - 115th Annual Report, 1959 (Reel 10, Page 1-107)
  - 116th Annual Report, 1960 (Reel 10, Page 1-126)
  - 117th Annual Report, 1961 (Reel 11, Page 1-130)
  - 118th Annual Report, 1962 (Reel 11, Page 1-133)
  - 119th Annual Report, 1963 (Reel 11, Page 1-108)
  - 120th Annual Report, 1964 (Reel 11, Page 1-120)
  - 121st Annual Report, 1965 (Reel 11, Page 1-116)
  - 122nd Annual Report, 1966 (Reel 11, Page 1-120)
  - 123rd Annual Report, 1967 (Reel 11, Page 1-111)
  - 124th Annual Report, 1968 (Reel 11, Page 1-120)
  - 125th Annual Report, 1969 (Reel 11, Page 1-117)
  - 126th Annual Report, 1970 (Reel 11, Page 1-114)
  - 127th Annual Report, 1971 (Reel 11, Page 1-112)
  - 128th Annual Report, 1972 (Reel 11, Page i-xiv, 1-111)
  - 129th Annual Report, 1973-1974 (Reel 11, Page 1-35)
  - 130th Annual Report, 1975 (Reel 11, Page 1-31)
  - 131st Annual Report, 1976 (Reel 11, Page 1-40)
  - 132nd Annual Report, 1977 (Reel 11, Page 1-32)
  - 133rd Annual Report, 1978 (Reel 11, Page 1-26)
  - 134th Annual Report, 1979 (Reel 11, Page 1-35)
- Prison Visits Files, ca. 1915; 1962; 1974-1985; 3; 1.33 cubic ft.
  This series consists of material generated in connection with the Correctional Association's statutory responsibility for inspecting jails, prisons, and adolescent detention facilities in New York State. Documents in this series were created by the Association's General Secretary, Institutions Visiting Committee, and other personnel and include correspondence, prison visit reports, prison tour requests, memoranda, affidavits, and other court records. Also included are records concerning Correctional Association President Adam McQuillan's 1977 visit to the Southern Ohio Correctional Facility. The only document from circa 1915 is a pamphlet describing a traveling exhibition concerning the New York State prison system.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Adolescent Detention and Reception Center and Adolescent Detention Center, Rikers Island [RESTRICTED], 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albion Correctional Facility, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arthur Kill Correctional Facility, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Attica Correctional Facility, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Attica Visiting Committee [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bayview Correctional Facility, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bedford Hills Correctional Facility, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bronx House of Detention, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn House of Detention, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn House of Detention - Affadavits [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chinlund v. New York City Department of Corrections [RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clinton Correctional Facility - Cancellation of Visit, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - County Jails - Dutchess [RESTRICTED], 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - County Jails - Genessee, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - County Jails - Monroe [RESTRICTED], 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - County Jails - Nassau [RESTRICTED], 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - County Jails - Rockland, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - County Jails - Suffolk, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - County Jails - Westchester, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Eastern New York Correctional Facility, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Fishkill Correctional Facility, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Great Meadow Correctional Facility, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Green Haven Correctional Facility, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Green Haven - Complaints to Commissioner, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Guidelines for Local Visiting Committees, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - House of Detention for Men (Rikers Island), 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - House of Detention for Men (Rikers Island), 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - House of Detention for Men (Rikers Island), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - House of Detention for Men (Rikers Island), 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - House of Detention for Men (Rikers Island) Transfer, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Institutions Visiting Committee, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Institutions Visiting Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Institutions Visiting Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Institutions Visiting Committee, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Institutions Visiting Committee, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Institutions Visiting Committee - Meetings and Visits, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Institutions Visiting Committee - Seminar on Corrections, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Institutions Visiting Committee - Training, Reports, and Correspondence [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Institutions Visits - Donald Goff, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous, ca. 1915; 1975; 1983; 1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - New York City Correctional Institute for Men, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - New York City Correctional Institute for Women, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - New York State Department of Corrections Guidelines, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - On the City's Master Plan (House of Detention for Men), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - On the City's Master Plan - Summary, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Prison-visiting Volunteers, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Ossining Correctional Facility - "Sing Sing", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Queensborough Correctional Facility, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Queens House of Detention, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Queens House of Detention - Branch, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Rikers Island Hospital, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Southern Ohio Correctional Facility, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Tables, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Taconic Correctional Facility, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Tombs [RESTRICTED], 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Tombs - Study Report, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Wallkill Correctional Facility, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Westchester County Visiting Committee, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Woodfield Cottage and Detention Center, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Narcotics Committee Files, 1949; 1962-1972; 1975; 4; 1 cubic foot
  This series was created by the Association's Narcotics Committee, which apparently kept its records separate from other material generated by members of the Board of Directors. It contains reports, pamphlets, articles, brochures, memoranda, news clippings, and some correspondence. Among the subjects covered are: the New York State [?] Narcotics Addiction Control Commission, drug rehabilitation programs, the Federal Bureau of Narcotics, and methadone maintenance programs.
  - Marijuana, 1961-1972 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 1)
  - Methadone, 1965-1973 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 2)
  - Methadone, 1970 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 3)
  - Narcotics - Articles, 1962-1971; 3 folders (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 4)
  - Narcotics - Glasgow, 1967 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 5)
  - Narcotics Addiction Control Commission - New York State, 1967 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 6)
  - Narcotics Addiction Control Commission - Folder 1, 1966-1969 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 7)
  - Narcotics Addiction Control Commission - Folder 2, 1966-1972 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 8)
  - Narcotics Addiction Rehabilitation - Folder 1, 1971-1973 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 9)
  - Narcotics Addiction Rehabilitation - Folder 2, 1965-1972 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 10)
  - Narcotics Committee Correspondence, 1965-1972 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 11)
  - Narcotics, Federal Bureau of, 1949-1972 (Box 1 (4-Narcotics Committee Files), Folder 12)
- Program and Bureau Files, 1967-1983; 5; 1.66 cubic ft.
  This series contains material created or collected by Correctional Association staffers responsible for operating programs that furnished direct services to inmates and their families. The Association's Family Services Bureau, Legal Services Bureau, and Social Services Bureau were long-term programs that were phased out during the late 1970s and early 1980s. Programs established during the 1980s were grant-funded demonstration projects designed to encourage emulation; the Association did not have the financial resources needed to sustain long-term social service programs. Of interest particular interest is the Association's short-term program to furnish counseling services to young offenders sent to the Adolescent Reception and Detention Center on Rikers Island (1981-1982). Also of interest are the documents generated in connection with the Association's efforts to establish an Ombudsman Program (1972-1973) and the ensuing resistance of Governor Nelson Rockefeller and state corrections officials.
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Application and Contracts, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Correctional Association Task Force, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Correspondence [RESTRICTED], 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Correspondence - Key, K. Michael (Counselor) [RESTRICTED], 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Counseling Project, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Counselors' Reports [RESTRICTED], 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Foundation Appeal, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Freggans, Richard [RESTRICTED], 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Monthly Statistics, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Orientation Booklet, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Resumes/Personnel, 1980? (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Statistical Data Forms [RESTRICTED], 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Status Report, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Vouchers, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Adolescent Reception and Detention Center - Women Offenders Report [RESTRICTED], 1981? (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Children of Offenders Program - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Children of Offenders Program - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Children of Offenders Program - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Children of Offenders Program - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration - Grant Proposal, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Children of Offenders Program - Law Enforcement Assistance Administration - Grant Proposal and Budget, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Family Prison Visiting Program, 1967-1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Family Services Bureau - Christmas, 1967-1980 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Family Services Bureau - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Legal Services Bureau - Interim Reports, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Legal Services Bureau - Reports, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Ombudsman, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ombudsman - Bedford Hills, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Ombudsman - News Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Ombudsman - Committee, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ombudsman - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ombudsman - Fundraising, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ombudsman - Program Agencies, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Ombudsman - Program Agencies, 1971-1978 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Ombudsman - Proposal, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Proposal - Alcoholism Program, ca. 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Proposal - Lengthy Detention Program, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Social Services [RESTRICTED], 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Social Services - Correspondence - Friedlander, Shelley (Director) [RESTRICTED], 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Social Services - Correspondence - Friedlander, Shelley (1 of 2)[RESTRICTED], 1977; 2 folders (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Social Services - Correspondence - Friedlander, Shelley (2 of 2)[RESTRICTED], 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Social Services - Correspondence - Friedlander, Shelley [RESTRICTED], 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Social Services - Correspondence - Friedlander, Shelley [RESTRICTED], 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Social Services - Reports, 1973-1981 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Project Files, 1974-1988; 6; 3.33 cubic ft.
  This series consists of material created or collected by Correctional Association staffers and board members engaged in short-term projects designed to produce written reports about various aspects of the correctional system; copies of many of these reports are included. Of particular interest are the Case Histories Project (1983-1985), Idle Time Project (1981-1985), and the Prison and Jail Conditions Project (1982-1986), which entailed extensive surveys of conditions and inmate programs available in New York State correctional facilities and generated correspondence and other material from inmates. Also of note is the Prison Mental Hygiene Project (1985-1988) that documents the programs and resources then available to prisoners with mental illness and developmental disabilities. Two of the projects, the State Planning Project (1981-1982) and the Prison Overcrowding Project (1982-1984), concern crowding in prisons and alternatives to new prison construction. This series also contains material generated in connection with the AIDS in Prison Project (1985-1988), the Budget Education Project (1983-1985), the Latino Project (1985-1988), and proposals for several other projects that the Association did not complete.
  - AIDS in Prison Project, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AIDS in Prison Project, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Budget Education Project, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Budget Education Project, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Budget Education Project - Allies, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budget Education Project - Allies - State and City, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget Education Project - Batch Application, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Budget Education Project - Calculations, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Budget Education Project - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Budget Education Project - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Budget Education Project - Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Budget Education Project - Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Budget Education Project - Correspondence - New York City Office of Management and Budget, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Budget Education Project - Cost of Corrections, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Budget Education Project - Counterbudget, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Budget Education Project - "Hidden Costs of Incarceration" - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Budget Education Project - "Hidden Costs of Incarceration" - Media, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Budget Education Project - Matthias, Robert, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Budget Education Project - New York City Jail Crisis, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Budget Education Project - New York City Jail Crisis - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Budget Education Project - New York City Jail Crisis - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Budget Education Project - Monthly Financial Reports, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Budget Education Project - Number 2, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Budget Education Project - Prison Operating Costs, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Budget Education Project - Prison Operating Costs - Press Release, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Budget Education Project - Proposal, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Budget Education Project - Proposal, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Budget Education Project - Public Safety, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Budget Education Project - Statewide Youth Advocates, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Budget Education Project - Steelman, Diane, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Budget Education Project - Steelman, Diane - Reports, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Budget Education Project - What Price Safety?, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Case Histories Project, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Case Histories Project - Correspondence [RESTRICTED], 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Case Histories Project - Do They Belong in Prison? [RESTRICTED], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Case Histories Project - Do They Belong in Prison? - Advance Copies Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Case Histories Project - Do They Belong in Prison - Advance Copy, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Case Histories Project - Proposal, 1982/1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Case Histories Project - Release Forms [RESTRICTED], 1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Idle Time Project - "Doing Idle Time" [RESTRICTED], 1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Idle Time Project - "Doing Idle Time" - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Idle Time Project - "Doing Idle Time" - Interviews and Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Idle Time Project - "Doing Idle Time" - Report Mailing List and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Idle Time Project - "Doing Idle Time" - Press Coverage, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Idle Time Project - Other States, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Idle Time Project - Proposal and Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Idle Time Project - Prison Alcohol Programs, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Adirondack Correctional Facility, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Albion, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Idle Time Project - Arthur Kill, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Auburn, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Bayview, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Bedford Hills, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Clinton, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Collins, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Coxsackie, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Downstate, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Eastern/Naponoch, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Elmira, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Fishkill, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Great Meadow/Comstock [RESTRICTED], 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Green Haven, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Groveland, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Hudson, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Lincoln, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Long Island/Pilgrim/Brentwood, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Mid - Orange, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Ogdensburg, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Otisville, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Sing Sing (Ossining) [RESTRICTED], 1922-1984 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Survey - Taconic, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Wallkill, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Watertown, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Idle Time Project - Survey - Woodburne, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Latino Project, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Latino Project - Impact of Prison on Inner City Black and Latino Communities, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New York City Pretrial Detention Project, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Director Search, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Meeting Announcements, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Neglected Population - Bayview Advisory Board, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Neglected Population - Commissioner's Response, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Neglected Population - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Neglected Population - Requests, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Neglected Population: Women Prisoners at Bayview, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Outline, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Policymaker Education, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Potler, Cathy - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Potler, Cathy - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Potler, Cathy - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Potler, Cathy - Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Proposal and Budget, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Proposal, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - State of the Prisons, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Prison and Jail Conditions Project - Third Year Proposal, 1986? (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene and AIDS Projects - Public Officials, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Alliance for the Mentally Ill of Westchester County, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - AMI Interviews, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Attica - Eng v. Smith, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Background Reports, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Crime and Mental Illness, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Deinstitutionalization, 1978-1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Epilepsy, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Ex-mental Patients in Criminal Justice System, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - General, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Grants and Budget, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Media, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Mental Health Alternatives to Incarceration Program, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Prison Mental Hygiene Project - Mental Health Literature, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 37)